<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dr Barnaby Smith</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Dr Barnaby Smith</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 11:22:33 +1200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Privacy policy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/privacy-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Apr 2022 11:22:33 +1200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/privacy-policy/</guid>
      <description> Privacy policy </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contact/</guid>
      <description> Contact Name * Email * Message * Send </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/patient-registration-form/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/patient-registration-form/</guid>
      <description>Patient Registration Form Family Name * Given Name * Preferred Name Name of Guardian (if dependant/minor) Address * Phone number * Email Address * Date of birth * Occupation Family Doctor Medical Insurer If Southern Cross: SC Member Number Regular Medications Medication Allergies Other Medical Conditions Select Location Tauranga Specialist Centre East Bay Specialist Centre I authorize Dr Barnaby Smith to obtain laboratory results and additional medical Information from my GP, the laboratory or other specialist, which may be required to complete your consultation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/</guid>
      <description>Proceedures</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/anti-reflux-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/anti-reflux-surgery/</guid>
      <description>Upper Gastrointestinal Anti reflux surgery Reflux Oesophagitis and Anti-Reflux Surgery Reflux Oesophagitis is a common condition where an excess of gastric juices (Mostly acidic) inappropriately rise up the Oesophagus. This is usually either due to an excess of acid production or incompetent (non-functioning) valve. The latter may benefit from surgery. The symptoms of reflux are common in the community and most patients are adequately treated by Proton-Pump inhibitor medications (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/laparoscopic-hernia-complications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/laparoscopic-hernia-complications/</guid>
      <description>Laparoscopic Hernia Laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair Complications Recovery Complications Bleeding and infection rates are very low. Occasionally there can be bruising in the inguinal region.&#xA;Recurrence rates for the Laparoscopic inguinal hernia is approximately 1%, this is similar to the traditional Open inguinal hernia repair. Conversion to an Open Inguinal hernia (i.e. larger scar) repair occurs in less than 1%. Post operative chronic pain is less with laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/laparoscopic-hernia-mesh-controversy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/laparoscopic-hernia-mesh-controversy/</guid>
      <description>Laparoscopic Hernia Laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair Complications Recovery Mesh Controversy Recently there has been some discussion into the validity of mesh. This was due to the use of mesh in repair of the pelvic floor (not inguinal hernias). Mesh placed incorrectly can cause problems.&#xA;Mesh is indicated in inguinal hernia repairs and has been used successfully for over 30 years. The NZ General Surgical Association recently released a statement affirming the above.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/laparoscopic-hernia-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/laparoscopic-hernia-recovery/</guid>
      <description>Laparoscopic Hernia Laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair Complications Recovery Recovery You will be given pain relief to go home with. The water-proof dressings can be removed after 4 days. The Steri-strips beneath these can be left until they start to come away (usually 7 days). The scars will be closed with a dissolving suture.&#xA;Driving is to be avoided until you can perform the emergency brake without hesitation (usually 3-4 days).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/laparoscopic-hernia/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/laparoscopic-hernia/</guid>
      <description>Laparoscopic Hernia Laparoscopic inguinal hernia repair Complications Recovery Keyhole repair of inguinal hernia The Laparoscopic inguinal hernia (Totally Extra Peritoneal; TEP) surgery is a technique to repair your hernia with three small scars placing the mesh in the preperitoneal plane. This has a number of advantages&#xA;Improved recovery Less chronic pain The mesh is in a more physiologically appropriate layer of the abdominal wall Indicated in repair of recurrent hernia Indicated in bilateral hernia (both left and right) Preoperative cares You may be told to discontinue your blood thinning agents preoperatively.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-after-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-after-recovery/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist After Recovery After surgery, your weight will continue to decrease and soon you will have recovered physically from the surgery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-choosing-op/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-choosing-op/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist Choosing the right operation for you Once you have decided that weight loss surgery is for you, the next major step is which operation is best for you.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-clinical-nurse-specialist/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-clinical-nurse-specialist/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist Clinical Nurse Specialist Sharon Hilton Sharon is a Registered Nurse with over 30 years&#39; of experience.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-cost/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-cost/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist Cost The cost of surgery includes Private hospital, Surgical and Anaesthetist charge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-dietician-advice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-dietician-advice/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist Dietician advice Before your Surgery What is Optifast? Optifast is a meal replacement which is very low in calories and high in protein.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-gastric-bypass/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-gastric-bypass/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist Roux-en-Y Gastric Bypass A Gastric Bypass is a major operation to create a small stomach pouch and rearrange the small bowel to partially &#34;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-gastric-sleeve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-gastric-sleeve/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist Sleeve Gastrectomy Sleeve gastrectomy is the removal of a large part of your stomach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-gp-info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-gp-info/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist GP info Nutritional deficiencies - What to look for post bariatric surgery Protein malnutrition / protein energy malnutrition Protein malnutrition can occur for a number of reasons including poor dietary choice, anastomotic stricture or protein malabsorption (short gut).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-omega-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-omega-loop/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist The omega loop gastric bypass (mini-loop gastric bypass) The Omega Loop is the reduction in the size of your stomach and re-arrangement of your small bowel such that the mixing of digestive enzymes/ bile (required for the breakdown of calories/vitamins) with swallowed food is delayed (bypassed) to decrease absorption.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-optifast-diet-instructions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-optifast-diet-instructions/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist Optifast Diet Instructions You will have told you how long you need to follow this diet before surgery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-patient-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-patient-journey/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist Bariatric flowchart Patient journey * Clinical Nurse Specialists (CNS) phone calls throughout.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-post-gastric/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-post-gastric/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist POST OP PROTOCOL; Gastric Bypass Day 0: Day of surgery May have sips of water up to 30mls per hour Encourage mobilisation IV Omeprazole as charted STOP all diabetic medication Regular anti-emetic as charted Strict fluid balance - show patient how to record this themselves Sub-cut Clexane as charted TEDS should still be in place from admission Day 1: Post op Start sips of water 30ml/hr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-post-operative-bloods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-post-operative-bloods/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist Post operative blood tests Blood Procedure Frequency of Monitoring HbA1c Sleeve gastrectomy Gastric bypass As appropriate in those with preoperative diabetes U+E, LFT, FBC, ferritin, folate, Calcium, vitamin D, PTH Sleeve gastrectomy Gastric bypass At 3, 9 months in the first year, then annually.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-post-operative/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-post-operative/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist Postoperative vitamin and element replacement After a Gastric Bypass you are more likely to develop vitamin and elemental deficiencies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-post-sleeve/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-post-sleeve/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist POST OP PROTOCOL; Sleeve gastrectomy Day 0: Day of surgery May have sips of water up to 30mls per hour Encourage mobilisation IV Omeprazole as charted STOP all diabetic medication Regular anti-emetic as charted Strict fluid balance - show patient how to record this themselves Sub-cut Clexane as charted TEDS should still be in place from admission Day 1: Post op Start sips of water 30ml/hr.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-preparing-for-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery-preparing-for-surgery/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist Preparing for surgery Prior to Very Low Calorie Diet (i.e. OptiFast) Guidelines may vary from person to person, but may include the following: Eliminate or decrease saturated fats, including whole milk products, fatty meat, and fried food Eliminate or decrease foods that are high in carbohydrates, such as sugary desserts, pasta, potatoes, bread, and bread products Eliminate high-sugar beverages, such as juice and sodas Exercise portion control Avoid binge eating Don&#39;t smoke cigarettes Avoid alcoholic beverages and recreational drugs Don&#39;t drink beverages with your meals You may take protein supplements as protein shakes or powder Very Low Calorie Diet (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/procedures/weight-loss-surgery/</guid>
      <description>Bariatric (Weight Loss) Surgery How it works Gastric Sleeve Choosing op Omega Loop Patient journey Preparing for surgery Optifast diet instructions Post operative Vitamin and Element replacement Post Gastric Bypass fluids and discharge plan Post Sleeve gastrectomy fluids and discharge plan Dietician Advice After recovery Post operative bloods GP info Cost Roux en Y Gastric Bypass Clinical Nurse Specialist How does weight loss surgery work? The Gastrointestinal tract (gut) is a complex system of hormones, enzymes and feedback-systems that control the absorption of food, the bodies response to and desire for more food (Satiety).</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
